Finding Aid for the Alan Reed Papers LSC.1222
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alan Reed papers
circa 1931-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
Reed, Alan
LSC.1222
9.4 Linear Feet (1 box, 2 oversize boxes, and 1 oversize folder)
Alan Reed (1907-1977) performed on Broadway (1930s-40s), and appeared in more than 50 films, including The postman always rings twice and Breakfast at Tiffany's. He also played character roles on television, most notably, as the voice of cartoon character Fred Flintstone (1960-77). The collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, typescripts, photographs, sheet music, and scrapbooks from Alan Reed's career as a character actor in radio, television, and film.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Alan Reed, 1978.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9927230453606533
Biography
Born as Teddy Bergman, New York City, August 20, 1907; attended American Academy of Dramatic Arts and Columbia University; acting debut, Provincetown Theatre, Greenwich Village, 1927; performed on Broadway, 1930s-40s; worked in radio as a straight man with Eddie Cantor and Fred Allen among many other assignments; went to Hollywood in 1943 and appeared in more than 50 films, including The postman always rings twice, Marjorie Morningstar, and Breakfast at Tiffany's; founded Alan Reed Enterprises, an advertising specialities and business gifts sales firm, in 1955; appeared on television in character roles and, most notably, as the voice of cartoon character Fred Flintstone, 1960-77; died June 14, 1977.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, typescripts, photographs, sheet music, and scrapbooks from Alan Reed's career as a character actor in radio, television, and film. Includes a Fred Flintstone poster.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Manuscripts.
Radio material.
Television material (the Flintstones).
Clippings, sheet music, and photographs.
Oversize materials.
Actors -- United States -- Archives; Reed, Alan -- Archives
- Manuscript Material by Alan Reed
  - The barber of television street ... a situation comedy with ramifications. Beverly Hills., n.d.; (3 leaves, typescript) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yabba Dabba Doo or Never a star. A novel by Alan Reed. Los Angeles., n.d.; (ca. 65 leaves, bound photocopy with loose pages inserted at back) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Room 242 - Homocide. A new radio presentation by Alan Reed and Joel Murcott. Beverly Hills., c1950; (32 leaves, mimeograph with green cover) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ---. Another copy. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "It's happened before" or "Me and Abe Lincoln." n.p., ca. 1970; (3 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Radio Material
  - Correspondence from Fred Allen to Alan Reed. v.p., v.d.; (6 items: 8 leaves, and envelope with photocopies of typescript letters) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dialogue. n.p., v.d.; (66 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon with holograph corrections) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Scripts (Box 1, Folder 8-22)
    - Armed Forces Radio Service. "Command performance," no.258. Los Angeles., December 3, 1946; (22 leaves, mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bob Hope spot. n.p., n.d.; (5 leaves, typescript and mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Chesterfield Supper Club starring Perry Como. n.p., n.d.; (4 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Chesterfield Supper Club starring Perry Como. n.p., February 4, 1946.; (12 leaves, mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Chesterfield Supper Club starring Perry Como. n.p., March 11, 1946.; (8 leaves, mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Chesterfield Supper Club starring Perry Como. n.p., March 25, 1946.; (13 leaves, typescript, typescript carbon and mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Chesterfield Supper Club starring Perry Como. n.p., June 28, 1946.; (3 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - George Jessel. n.p., n.d.; (15 leaves, typescript carbon and mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Harrison of Homicide. A new dramatic mystery series. no.1. The case of the alter ego. Written by Irwin Ashkenazy. n.p., c1950.; (27 leaves, mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - The heart of the news. n.p., n.d.; (5 leaves, mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Mars audition. n.p., June 6, 1950.; (5 leaves, mimeograph with holograph corrections) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Texaco Star Theatre. n.p., n.d.; (10 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Tim and Irene (Ryan) spot. n.p., (8 leaves, mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Tom Howard. n.p., n.d.; (3 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Walter O'Keefe Show. n.p., n.d.; (7 leaves, mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Toasts. n.p., n.d.; (4 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon) (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Television Material
  General note
  Alan Reed was the voice of Fred Flintstone in the animated television series The Flintstones, a Hanna-Barbera production, ca. 1960-1966.
  - Clippings. v.p., v.d.; (5 items) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Photographs and ephemera. v.p., v.d.; (8 items) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Script material (Box 1, Folder 26-34)
    - Alan Reed as Fred Flintstone. n.p., n.d.; (11 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Alan Reed as Fred Flintstone (revised). n.p., n.d.; (13 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon with holograph corrections) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Alan Reed as Fred Flintstone (revised). n.p., n.d.; (3 leaves, typescript) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Flintstone Comedy Hour. Show no.1. n.p., n.d.; (1 leaves, mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Fred Flintstone and Friends. New opening title. 99-727. n.p., (3 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Fred Flintstone interview. n.p., n.d.; (5 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Fred Flintstone monologue. n.p., n.d.; (14 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon with holograph corrections) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Fred monologue. n.p., n.d.; (9 leaves, typescript, typescript carbon and photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Ordere of routines ... Flintstone act. n.p., n.d.; (2 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Miscellaneous Material
  - Clippings. n.p., n.d.; (16 items) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Knickerbocker Toy Company advertisements for "Kewtee Bear.", c1955.; (5 items) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "An oasis in Manhattan." A new comedy by S.K. Hershewe. n.p., ca. 1965.; (ca. 150 leaves, mimeograph with holograph notations) (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Photographs. v.p., v.d.; (16 items) (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Programs. v.p., v.d.; (12 items) (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Sheet Music - Lead Sheets (Box 1, Folder 40-45)
    - "I'm eating bread and butter (when it should be wedding cake).", c1955; (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - "I can't run away from you.", c1954; (1 item) (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - "Kewtee Bear.", c1954; (10 items) (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - "The Kewtee Bear song.", c 1956; (1 item) (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - "Remember me to Joe.", c1955; (4 items) (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - "Rootie tootie tootie" ("The Kewtee Bear song")., c.1955; (7 items) (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Oversize material.
  - Fred Flintstone poster., (1 item) (Folder 4)
  - Record album. Chesterfield Club. Alan Reed., June 28, 1945; (1 item, 78 rpm) (Box 2)
  - Scrapbooks, (3 items) (Box 2, Box 3)
    - Scrapbooks., 1932-1939 (Box 2)
    - Scrapbook., 1941-1972 (Box 3)